

PH.D. STUDENT

📞 +82-10-5269-2387 | 🖂 haneul.yoo@kaist.ac.kr | 🄏 haneul-yoo.github.io | 🐧 haneul-yoo | **in** haneulyoo | 💆 HaneulYoo13

About

Haneul Yoo is a Ph.D. student advised by Alice Oh in the School of Computing at KAIST. She will earn her M.S. degree in August and start her Ph.D. program in September. Her research interest primarily lies in the intersection of natural language processing and computational social science. In particular, she mainly works on (1) understanding historical documents in low-resource languages and (2) applying and utilizing NLP in language education. She believes there are still myriads of underrepresented languages in NLP, and our efforts on low-resource languages can build more culturally-diverse language models. She also believes language learners can contribute to NLP techniques and data and vice versa.

Education

KAISTDaejeon, Korea

Ph.D. IN School of Computing Sep 2022 - CURRENT

· Advisor: Alice Oh

KAISTDaejeon, Korea

M.S. IN SCHOOL OF COMPUTING Sep 2022 - Aug 2022

• Advisor: Alice Oh

Ajou University Suwon, Korea

B.S. DOUBLE MAJOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING AND DIGITAL MEDIA, GRADUATION WITH HONORS

Mar 2017 - Aug 2020

• University of Wisconsin - Stout, WI, USA — Semester Abroad Winter 2018

Experience _____

LAMDA Lab Suwon, Korea

RESEARCH INTERN Mar 2020 - Aug 2020

- Study of Deep Learning Model for Bio-signal (EEG) Analysis
- Advisor: Jungryul Seo and Kyung-Ah Sohn

KEPRI Daejeon, Korea

RESEARCH INTERN Sep 2019 - Feb 2020

- · Development of application services utilizing electric used power data
- · Advisor: Moonsuk Choi

CSIRO QLD, Australia

RESEARCH INTERN

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

- Convolutional deep neural network for detecting cattle in images/videos
- Advisor: Brano Kusy

Indielist Suwon, Korea

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & CO-FOUNDER

Jul 2018 - Jun 2019

• Establishment of an independent music platform and development of iOS application services

Publications _

Rethinking Annotation: Can Language Learners Contribute?

(under review)

HANEUL YOO, RIFKI AFINA PUTRI, CHANGYOON LEE, YOUNGIN LEE, SO-YEON AHN, DONGYEOP KANG AND ALICE OH

Jun 2022

Translating Hanja Historical Documents to Understandable Korean and English

arXiv preprint (under review)

JUHEE SON, JIHO JIN, HANEUL YOO, JINYEONG BAK, KYUNGHYUN CHO, AND ALICE OH

May 2022

HUE: Pretrained Model and Dataset for Understanding Hanja Documents of Ancient Korea

HANEUL YOO, JIHO JIN, JUHEE SON, JINYEONG BAK, KYUNGHYUN CHO, AND ALICE OH

NAACL Findings

Jul 2022

Knowledge-Enhanced Evidence Retrieval for Counterargument Generation

YOHAN JO, HANEUL YOO, JINYEONG BAK, ALICE OH, CHRIS REED, AND EDUARD HOVY

EMNLP Findings Nov 2021

Image-based Deep Learning Approach for EEG Signal Classification

HANEUL YOO, JUNGRYUL SEO, AND KYUNG-AH SOHN

KICS Summer Conference

Aug 2020

Mar 2020

Proposal and Simulation of Optimal Electric Vehicle Routing Algorithm

MOONSUK CHOI, INJI CHOI, MINHAE JANG, AND HANEUL YOO

KFPCO Journal

Talks and Teachings _____

KAIST SoC Colloquium (Fall 2021), Machine Learning (Spring 2021, Fall 2022)

Python at Suwon Information Science High School (Spring 2020), Java at Maetan High School (Spring 2019)

Academic Services

Volunteer FAccT (2022)

Reviewer NeurlPS Track on Datasets and Benchmarks (2021), EMNLP (2022)

Honors and Awards _____

Graduation with Honors Ajou University

SUMMA CUM LAUDE (1ST PLACE) Aug 2020

Outstanding Volunteer Award Gyeonggi Volunteer Center

Jun 2020

KIPA

Special Prize BIXPO 2019 Nov 2019

Excellence Award

CREATIVE START-UP COMPETITION Nov 2019

Academic Excellence Scholarship Asan Foundation

Mar 2017 - Aug 2020

Skills ___

Languages Python, JavaScript, C++, Java, Ruby, Swift

Frameworks PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Docker, AWS, Django, Flask, Vue, React